Hao Le

San Diego, California, US | UC Berkeley BA, CS | +1 (925) 301-3660 | haonhatle@gmail.com | github.com/haonle

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack engineer with 3 years of hands-on and full-cycle work experience designing, implementing, and testing business and presentation layers. Seeking to collaborate with other business functions and engineers to develop large-scale systems and responsive UIs with readable, testable, and maintainable code.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Time By Ping Inc

Oct 2019 - Jul 2022

- Collaborated closely with product and design teams and implemented half of client UI
- Coordinated closely with quality assurance teams over automated and manual testing specifications
- Designed and implemented backend features and RESTful api routes
- Updated backend queries and database indices to reduce IOPS by 25% and stopped thrashing
- Wrote unit, integration, and end-to-end tests for UI and RESTful API Server, increasing coverage by 10%
- Executed cleanup of 4 year legacy code and refactored thousand line classes, decreasing debugging time by 30%
- Peer-reviewed over a hundred PRs and mentored engineers on best practices
- Conducted coding, refactoring, and testing interviews
- Onboarded and trained 11 engineers to tools, processes, and codebases
- Investigated client performance issues and communicated findings with clients
- Reduced UI latency by 30-95% depending on feature breadth
- Provided and implemented changes to engineering process such as work estimation and testing criteria
- Onboarded client law firms with on-prem installations and integration to billing and document systems

SDE Intern, Amazon

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Designed and Implemented data validation package with unit tests for 500k monthly users
- Optimized code runtime for SLA compliance and maintained sub-second backend response
- Utilized dependency injection and integrated package across multiple petabyte-scale data sources
- Prepared working backwards product dev documentation and presented final project

Software Engineer Intern, Time By Ping Inc

May 2017 - Aug 2017 & Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

- Implemented Outlook integration for extracting tracking over 95% of email data with metrics and SLA adherence
- Built backend integration with corporate microsoft Exchange servers for email tracking service
- Researched cloud options and setup test Exchange servers in Azure
- Performed a code rewrite of a microservice from .Net to Node.js
- Designed and implemented RESTful api routes with unit tests for data consumption

PROJECTS

Clothing Image Recognition API

- Trained PyTorch CNN AI model on Fashion MNIST dataset: 70,000 28x28 labeled fashion images
- Developed, tested, and iterated model on Jupyter notebook and deployed API to Heroku

EDUCATION

UC Berkeley - BA, Computer Science

2015 - 2019

Lab Assistant and tutor for Data Structures and Algorithms course

Skills

Python, Java, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, node.js, React, Redux, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, .net, WPF